<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source Tutorials</title>
    <link>tayyabsayyad.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Open Source Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 19:53:57 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="tayyabsayyad.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Youtubedl</title>
      <link>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/tips/youtubedl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 19:53:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/tips/youtubedl/</guid>
      <description>Hi all, Just sharing a small trick on how to download a video from youtube using a command line tool youtube-dl.
You can find the entire documentation of this tool here https://rg3.github.io/youtube-dl/
Install using following command
sudo apt-get install youtube-dl  Once you install you can download videos using
youtube-dl link  Example lets download one of my favourite video
youtube-dl https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lSRYCc7ApHc&amp;amp;amp;index=42&amp;amp;amp;list=PL-bTaZrTDhtbhxgS59t4HzwCnq2iIYMgV  You can also download multiple videos from the playlist as follows</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self Signed Certificate</title>
      <link>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/tutorials/selfsignedcertificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 21:46:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/tutorials/selfsignedcertificate/</guid>
      <description>To secure your web server you need SSL certificate which can be obtained by two ways
 Generate a self-signed certificate Obtain from the third party like DigiCert or Thawte  Generate Self Signed Certificate Install openssl if not present using the following command
$sudo apt-get install openssl  Next step is to generate private keys which can be generated as follows, This will ask you to enter a password to protect this key and will generate key file named www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vi Editor</title>
      <link>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/linux/vi-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 21:46:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/linux/vi-editor/</guid>
      <description>Vi editor is a default editor in most of the Linux distributions.
Vi editor has three modes as follows,
Command Mode : In this mode, you can execute commands, whatever you type is considered as a command and executed on the current file.
Insert Mode : In this mode, you are editing the file. When you type it gets entered into the current file which you are working on. Execution mode : In this mode, you save, close, exit from the working file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Linux Mint Desktop on Ubuntu 16.04</title>
      <link>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/linux/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 21:46:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/linux/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>To install Linux Mint Desktop on Ubuntu 16.04 following are the steps
1. sudo add-apt-repository ppa:embrosyn/cinnamon 1. sudo apt update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt install cinnamon  Logout and Select Linux Mint from the Login Screen</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/tips/javasetpath/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/tips/javasetpath/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>