<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Open Source Tutorials</title>
    <link>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Open Source Tutorials</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 19:53:57 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Display todays files in Ubuntu </title>
      <link>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/tips/todayslist/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 19:53:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/tips/todayslist/</guid>
      <description>If you want to get list all files which you have created today then use following command
ls -al –time-style=+%D | grep `date +%D`  Option - Description
 l - Long listing of files a - all files including hidden files –time-style - Time display style grep - to find files only from given date date - to find todays date and then it gets substituted in grep  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding big files in terminal</title>
      <link>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/tips/listbigfiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 19:53:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/tips/listbigfiles/</guid>
      <description>You might often come across a situation where you want to find biggest files to delete to free space in your drives or home directory. I found this trick on
http://www.tuxradar.com/content/linux-tips-every-geek-should-know
Use following command to find big files in sorted order by size.
ls -lSrh It works as follows Option Meaning l - Long listing of files S - Sort by file size largest first r - Sorting list in reverse order h - Human Readable File Size If you want big file to appear first remove ‘r’ option You can also append listing criteria for specific files  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to remove unnecessary packages from Ubuntu ?</title>
      <link>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/tips/removeunnecessary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 19:53:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/tips/removeunnecessary/</guid>
      <description>In order to save space or to make your system work faster, you can do following steps you can use following tricks
 Remove all packages which got installed to satisfy dependency and now no more needed.
sudo apt-get autoremove
 Remove all packages which are downloaded for installation
sudo apt-get clean
 Remove files which can’t be downloaded or they are now useless.
sudo apt-get autoclean
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set Java Home in Ubuntu</title>
      <link>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/tips/javasetpath/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 19:53:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/tips/javasetpath/</guid>
      <description>Open terminal and open file /etc/profile
$sudo gedit /etc/profile  Copy your Java Home location as it can be in your home folder of open jdk
JAVA_HOME=”/home/tayyabali/jdk1.8.0_31/bin” or JAVA_HOME=”/usr/lib/jvm/open-jdk”
Append the home entry as following in the “profile file” following
export JAVA_HOME=$JAVA_HOME:/home/tayyabali/jdk1.8.0_31/bin  Use source command to load the variables, by running this command:
source /etc/environment  Then check the variable, by running this command:
echo $JAVA_HOME  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Youtube-dl</title>
      <link>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/tips/youtubedl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2018 19:53:57 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/tips/youtubedl/</guid>
      <description>Hi all, Just sharing a small trick on how to download a video from youtube using a command line tool youtube-dl.
You can find the entire documentation of this tool here https://rg3.github.io/youtube-dl/
Install using following command
sudo apt-get install youtube-dl  Once you install you can download videos using
youtube-dl link  Example lets download one of my favourite video
youtube-dl https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lSRYCc7ApHc&amp;amp;amp;index=42&amp;amp;amp;list=PL-bTaZrTDhtbhxgS59t4HzwCnq2iIYMgV  You can also download multiple videos from the playlist as follows</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self Signed Certificate</title>
      <link>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/tutorials/selfsignedcertificate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 21:46:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/tutorials/selfsignedcertificate/</guid>
      <description>To secure your web server you need SSL certificate which can be obtained by two ways
 Generate a self-signed certificate Obtain from the third party like DigiCert or Thawte  Generate Self Signed Certificate Install openssl if not present using the following command
$sudo apt-get install openssl  Next step is to generate private keys which can be generated as follows, This will ask you to enter a password to protect this key and will generate key file named www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vi Editor</title>
      <link>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/linux/vi-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 21:46:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/linux/vi-editor/</guid>
      <description>Vi editor is a default editor in most of the Linux distributions.
Vi editor has three modes as follows,
Command Mode : In this mode, you can execute commands, whatever you type is considered as a command and executed on the current file.
Insert Mode : In this mode, you are editing the file. When you type it gets entered into the current file which you are working on. Execution mode : In this mode, you save, close, exit from the working file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install Linux Mint Desktop on Ubuntu 16.04</title>
      <link>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/linux/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 21:46:34 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>tayyabsayyad.github.io/post/linux/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to install Linux Mint Desktop on Ubuntu 16.04
To install Linux Mint Desktop on Ubuntu 16.04 following are the steps
1. sudo add-apt-repository ppa:embrosyn/cinnamon 1. sudo apt update &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo apt install cinnamon  Logout and Select Linux Mint from the Login Screen</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>